those are all very helpful because we
can see as we start you know ascending
or as we start ascending it
um as we start assessing
[Music]
dude this is not the week for this topic
though it really is not man I I have had
I've had some problems with some
programs this week oh that's not good to
hear yeah I I um so I'm participating in
the uh you know in the Ambassador World
Cup you know we we did all right our
team did so so I think I think we'll
make it through we'll see but
um I had I had a crit
this week go internal dupe
on and it was a crit that had been there
for a while on an external surface and
I'm like come on man this is like a
competition
front this is a competition
you know program and they still had that
that dupe in place from for a while back
so I'm a little bit salty at the
programs this this this week so
hopefully we can still I can still bring
an unbiased perspective into this
episode on how to determine if a program
is good or not dang that's super
frustrating I've actually I I have I
don't know if this is a popular opinion
but my opinion is that if something is
an internal dupe and it's still open
after like
I don't know set your arbitrary time
frame six months a year you should just
pay for it anyways because I have to fix
it by that point what an attacker is
gonna exploit that right Nothing's Gonna
Stop an attacker this bug has been there
for five years Joel okay five about six
months I know I know I'm a little salty
I'm a little salty we're working it
we're working it through I'm not gonna
call the program out but
um yeah you can roast them you can tell
me their name after after I'll tell you
all fair all right let's let's get to
the news
um let's see what do we got today okay
so I just wanted to do a little shout
out real quick Jason came on the show
last week it was super fun having him on
um he actually released a tool
uh almost right as we aired last week or
a little bit before we recorded I think
um called AWS scrape which is a a go
tool to monitor AWS IP ranges and alert
for SSL certificate data so this is
going to be really cool if you're sorry
I just slapped my mic
um this is going to be really cool if
you are
um you know searching for assets that
are kind of ephemeral or are kind of
just popping up and so that you can be
uh write get jump right on attacking
them as soon as they pop up I used to do
this a lot I kind of edged out of the
Recon game but totally viable strategy
in my opinion yeah I feel like this is
kind of towing a good line between just
like an off-the-shelf tool and a Custom
home build like Recon continuous
checking type framework where you could
probably spin this into something pretty
easy to help you get a little more
visibility especially for say you're
targeting a specific program which we'll
talk about a little bit later but if
you're targeting like one specific
program and you want to like
continuously get alerts when they have
new infrastructure pop up it's probably
a really good way to do it yeah yeah for
sure so definitely be uh you know keep
that in mind if you're getting ready to
look at
um uh you know implementing something
like that for SSL certificates in your
recon flow
um
you want to take a talk about yeah
corropolis so that was kind of the big
news over the last week or two Yeah
so basically there was a vulnerability
within the Google pixel screenshotting
cropping mechanism
where if you ever wondered how you can
edit an image from your photos app and
then there's a revert button that
manages the magically reverted back to
its original state well this is kind of
how that works and this is abusing that
functionality essentially so they
figured out that at truncated to the end
of the image is essentially a lot of the
original image data then you can use
that to reconstruct it back to the
original image to view the full
uncropped data so if you took a
screenshot of a sensitive page with a
bunch of information on you crop it down
to just the little relevant part you
would be able to reverse that back and
then a couple days later they found that
the windows Snipping tool is also
vulnerable to the same type yeah so it
was a it was a zero day in uh in the
pixel stuff and then somebody replied
and was like hey it was interesting I I
took a screenshot with the Snipping Tool
it looks like it has a lot of that same
data on the end you might want to look
into that
do you know if it's like is this the
exact same process or is it just like
the Snipping Tool also sort of made that
similar mistake in embedding that
metadata it seems like it's almost
identical based on what
um the the researcher uh what was what
was his name yeah look at this crop yeah
so based on what the research the
researcher David uh Buchanan mentioned
it seems like it's very very similar
it's just a difference between like RGB
and
um rgba with like wow transparency dang
dude that's nuts yeah look at this it's
almost fully he got a almost fully
recovered image out of that yeah it's
super wild so it's a really interesting
really dangerous vulnerability
especially depending on the image
hosting service that you've used like I
think one of the examples was Discord
where this doesn't have to do with exif
data it's not like they're not stripping
metadata this is separate it's the image
file itself has extra data attached to
it that you would be able to use to
extract the original image so even if
you uploaded like a photo to this chord
five years ago or whatever that could
potentially that photo could be
vulnerable to this and you could extract
it so uh it's just something to be aware
of I know that he tweeted out some
preventative measures so for example one
of the measures that He suggests is from
a server side you could write a filter
within your uh your web
you know your web server basically like
an nginx uh Plug-In or something like
that
that would strip out the end data so
that you're only left with the original
image and that would work retroactively
and all that kind of stuff so there are
definitely
um options if this is something that you
like you or your company might be
struggling with but
um it's definitely one of those like
really gnarly bugs that is uh gonna have
a lot of mess surrounding it that's
going to be kind of hard to clean up
yeah man because any any picture cropped
within that you know in the past is out
there and there's nothing you can do to
really modify that at this point besides
yeah I guess if you're hosting an image
you can modify that by you know actually
modifying the file itself and stripping
off that data at the end but like who
wants to do that I know it sounds
awesome it's so wild dude one of the
it's funny because on the original tweet
thread somebody replied it was like Hey
so let's say I've been sending cropped
images from Google phones to Discord for
about uh six years oh no how [__] am I
and the like report the like researchers
replied and was like well it depends on
a few factors but given that there's six
years of images I would guess pretty
[__] oh my god dude yeah that's bad I
wonder did they um did they report this
to Google and did it get a bounty I'm
pulling it up right now let's see they
did report it to Google that was
actually the interesting thing I was
looking to see if it got a bounty and I
did not see it at least on the original
thread I'm sure they must have gotten
one
um unless there was some really weird S3
on Google's
on Google's internal issue tracker I
found it from if you go to the the blog
post exploiting a crop blips uh and then
you click on his his blog at the very
end there's like an issue tracker and
then yeah it says fixed uh s3p3
um but no Bounty assigned so I don't
know man if they didn't give a bounty
for that that's pretty whack because
that's a very impactful bug I think yeah
it's super wild it feels like one of
those things that would be worth like
you know 30k 50k 100K something like
that one of those really really
groundbreaking ones yeah so I do hope
that they got a bounty or we'll get one
soon and they might even be eligible
that might be one of those things that's
eligible for uh the Google Play rewards
thing oh yeah
but yeah really cool bug
um
it was really interesting if you haven't
given it a read go read the original
blog post because it's so interesting it
was another one of those kind of bugs
that just
popped up out of nowhere like by
accident and they were like I wonder if
this is possible and just kind of
explored that route and it ended up
being a really bad really critical
vulnerability so
it's a really interesting story it's a
really well written blog post and it's a
super super interesting vulnerability
yeah all together sometimes you just
gotta go after that Curiosity man you
got to feed that Curiosity because
sometimes it works it works itself into
some crazy bones like this one yeah cool
uh speaking of volts in really bad like
really critical core
modules you want to talk about the ssrf
that doyan suck found yeah man that that
was pretty gnarly so uh this was another
blog post actually this one came out
almost two weeks ago now but it's I just
seen it recently this is a uh ssrf
filter bypass in uh node requests
Library which is a pretty pretty poor
Library
um and so it looks like just from
reading this over uh the tldr of it is
essentially if you redirect if you do a
redirect to localhost or something like
that when you're using this ssrf request
filter plug-in
um in it and that request is the same um
uses the same scheme so HTTP website to
http website then it catches it but if
you send it to an https website and
originally and then you redirect to an
HTTP website then somehow it just
bypasses the whole check and if you look
at the code in this in this Vlog dude
look at this it's just oh my gosh it's
ridiculous request to write protocols
yeah and then it literally just skips
the whole thing if you don't have
just like I'll just delete the agent
yeah yeah
um so it's kind of nuts this is not
something that I was testing for
um let's see first disclosure to
maintainer was 20 uh 2022 in December so
um if you know your company's having
passworded us this very well may still
be out there
um and definitely something to take a
look at and I think this is particularly
nasty because like for for example well
I imagine a lot of people just use HTTP
for their little like POC redirect
server right because no one really wants
to like spin up you know get an SSL
certificate especially those people that
are doing sort of cloud first and just
kind of spinning up stuff when they need
it a lot of that stuff is going to be
HTTP based I'd imagine and this is also
probably going to have
um as a cell verification so it's not
like you can just spin up like a temp
SSL certificate or anything so
definitely something to be keeping in
mind and test with get you know a full
https set up on your on your you know
testing callback server and do a
redirect from https to HTTP and see if
you can bypass some of those HTTP
filters or those um those redirect
filters on ssrfs yeah I think it's a
tester this would be something I would
probably just put in my normal testing
criteria
for from uh exploitability perspective
it does seem like it has just like
basically one mitigating factor which is
that the root is through this agent
thing and I hadn't actually heard about
I I wasn't familiar with what the agent
was or what it was used for and it looks
like it's essentially a way for you to
manage connections within like an
application so if you want to reuse
connections for more efficiency or that
type or if you want to filter certain
connections that was the example that
was given
um then you could do it with an agent
and so basically when it changes
protocols it deletes the agent
and so all of your checks that might be
within your agent get bypassed so if
you're a hacker and you don't know like
are they using an agent or not give it a
test and if you're a company and you're
not sure if you're vulnerable just look
and see if you're using an agent and if
you're not you're probably okay but if
you can upgrade just do it get your get
your source code gripping tools ready
because yeah that's going to be pretty
bad I think this would also you know be
fixed by a decent patch cycle you know
if you if you're patching your stuff on
a regular basis and making sure that
these core libraries like request are up
to date then you should be fine too but
that doesn't always happen as we know
true
cool
um let's see zdi was the only other
thing that I wanted to talk about dude
they had like a crazy so we don't really
I guess in my sphere of bug Bounty we're
mostly talking about
hacker one and Bug crowd and integrity
and all them and I I don't hear us
talking about zdi quite as much but
every time the competition pops up it's
pretty exciting and I kind of want to go
for it at some point like I I've only
done hacker One Life hacking events I've
done a bug crowd one uh I think maybe I
did two bug crowd ones but besides that
just hacker one and the zdi model seems
pretty pretty cool
um they just kind of give you some
Targets in advance and you earn these
masters of pone and uh you know
obviously large sums of money in
conjunction with them and I think a
couple teams actually the Tesla was a uh
was a target for some of these teams and
uh synactive and then one other team uh
let's see if I can find it yeah one
other team yeah they they also uh
opponed the Tesla which is kind of nuts
um and I think they walked away with
250k which is crazy yeah super crazy it
was really interesting to see the recap
it's cool because uh the re I think the
recap was just a couple days ago and it
looks like they paid out just over a
million dollars oh man to the teams so
all in all I mean that's up to par even
past some of the live hacking events
that we've been to
um and it's really awesome to see that
kind of research I think we don't talk a
lot about zdi because and I'm not sure
how much this is still the case but at
least early on they were kind of like
the
like black sheep of the bug Bounty world
where it wasn't really it wasn't like
official like you're not reporting it
directly to the company and stuff right
take a look at their website it seems
like they're more like legit and stuff
but it is still kind of a weird profit
incentive to think about like basically
you're selling the vulnerability to the
CDI and then they're gonna work with the
vendor and stuff to help like disclose
it but they still have that bug in the
middle and it's a little bit
a little bit interesting to think about
what they might be doing with that bug
if anything all that kind of stuff I'm
not going to speculate too much but you
can probably use your imagination and
yeah yeah no absolutely and you know I
hope the sponsors are involved you know
straight from the beginning you know
straight from when the reports come in
um one of the other things that I've
heard about DDI which is a little bit
interesting is you have a five minute
slot so these are fully formed exploits
let me just let me just say that as well
and these are not normally like I mean
sometimes they have like you know hit
this web endpoint and get an RC uh
exploits but a lot of the times when you
see the the write-ups for them they're
talking about you know binary
exploitation stuff
um and one of the so you and I you know
you remember when we were working on
that bug that we still haven't talked
about but it took a couple minutes but
then it took over the whole device right
right so I was researching because that
because I was like all right you know
this this device had been a target for a
zdi in the past and I was like oh
wouldn't it be cool if we could have
done it at the at the event I was
searching a little bit and one of the
things that it I found was that when
you're demoing your bug for the
competition for the Pontoon competition
the exploit has to successfully trigger
in a five minute window
which is pretty freaking short and
sounds hella stressful because like if
you're if you're doing like race
conditions if you're doing you know any
of these uh complex attacks that we've
been talking about with like brute
forcing that might take a little bit of
time but you pone the device in the end
you know those might not be eligible for
this attack or for this you know for
this bounty through zdi
um and yeah I think that's a little bit
unfortunate because you know I think
there's going to be some there's some
good bugs they're missing out on on that
yeah it's really interesting I think
it's kind of cool that it's it's sort of
a culmination like it you have to
perform well right it's not just for
having the cool bug you also it also has
to work basically basically first time
right it has to be a perfectly executed
exploit chain and I assume you have to
do this on like a brand new device right
so they bring in like a brand new
motherboard or whatever from the Tesla
and they're like sure exploit this and
you just hope that your testing device
was on the same version and then
everything works the same and all that
kind of stuff because if it doesn't then
there goes your 250k yeah for sure and
I'm looking through here it says on one
of their tweets for March 24th his Star
Labs team was not able to get their
exploit on Microsoft teams working in
the allotted amount of time and I'm like
oh that's gotta kill that's got to be so
and I'm sure they all went back to the
lab and got it working in five minutes I
know and you know we We complain about
dupes and stuff like that but like this
guy is literally you know they have this
fully formed exploit and then it just
you know something messes up and and
they couldn't get it in for five minutes
and now that that cost goes to much
lower I'm sure their prize goes to much
lower so kind of unfortunate but it
still looks like a fun thing I'm not
sure I would go all at it and like try
to hit all these different devices that
they're doing but
um I would definitely definitely take a
stab at some of the hardware devices
because we've been focusing on that a
little bit more lately and that's been
that's been really fun so yeah for sure
all right um let's see where do we want
to go from here we can dive right into
yeah let's dive right into it okay so
first let's we're so our topic for today
is how to determine if a program is a
good is a good program
um I think this is going to help people
when you're starting out in bug Bounty
you're not exactly
um familiar with what uh indicators you
should look for in a good program so
Joel and I are going to talk about some
of the things we look at when we look at
a bounty brief and kind of talk through
what it means for us to be uh sort of a
good program so
um Joel I'm going to put you on the spot
man hit me with some of your top program
I guess well I guess we can't because
they're going to be private programs in
there too can you talk about any of your
top you know your top favorite programs
I'm gonna go check if one of Mines is is
probably sure and I'll just Surprises by
like most of them are in the World Cup
right now but um Yahoo
uh Shopify
um
those are probably my top two
and then
I don't know if I can list the third one
because it's a private program so yeah
um yeah those are probably my top two
and I'll say the main reasons at least
like up right off the top of my head
we'll go into these but it's uh how easy
it is and how adaptable they are towards
like actual hackers hacking on their
program for example preceding accounts
letting you sign up with we are hacker
one that kind of stuff yeah and just
ability to triage ability to have good
payouts ability to handle things in an
efficient manner ability to
um have a wide enough scope for you to
stay interested for long periods of time
like those things are kind of difficult
it's not I I'm praising it as ability to
right but it's not really an ability
it's like do you have lots of servers
yes or no it's right nothing there's no
like inherent ability that you have lots
of servers yeah no that that makes sense
those are definitely some top indicators
for me I've got instacart and PayPal on
my list I really like those two programs
the third one I would really like to
shout out but it's a private program
um I'm just gonna say it's a big bank
and they have a responsible disclosure
program on hacker one and yeah they just
you know
really
you know cool I'm trying to think of
some you know inverted way to tell you
who it is but let's just say they're the
one that I want to hack on okay yeah
okay subtle oh okay
I I didn't say anything I can't be held
liable
um so so
um yeah those are my top three and I'll
I'll I'll double click into that for
just a second so instacart um has been a
really good program to me
um I'm gonna go pull up my you know
their their uh page really quick and
kind of talk through some of the reasons
why that's the case
um first of all the Bounty ranges are
really competitive so if you pull up
their brief um insta or hack1.com
instacart
um 20K crits 7 500 highs 3K mediums 500
lows obviously these are so this is
something I'll point out that maybe a
lot of newcomers would miss when you see
these numbers it says right underneath
there payouts are our typical maximum
for a submission based on severity so
just because it says 3K for medium
doesn't mean you're going to get 3K for
a medium you could get 501 dollars for a
medium because that's the range between
low and medium so I want to keep that in
mind but also the instacart team has
been very responsive
um very willing to uh you know pay good
bounties based off of impact assessment
that I've kind of talked through with
them and I think that's really important
in a program
yeah and I think that highlights a lot
of the same things that I talked about
where like when you're hacking on
something long term and a lot you want a
good working relationship with the
program essentially right so you want to
be able to communicate with them
efficiently you want them to appreciate
the work that you're putting in as much
as the work that they're putting in to
fix it right yeah and talk with you and
have payouts and maintain the report and
all that kind of stuff it takes effort
from both sides and so I think when
there's sort of that mutual respect from
both the program and the hacker that
adds a lot of value to your hacking
experience yeah yeah I think that means
and and I think that mutual respect can
be shown a lot of ways it can be respect
for each other's time by responding
quickly to you know uh responses on the
report it can be communicating in a
professional way
um so many times you see the uh what is
it bloody Taxi Driver report kind of pop
up in in hacker one circles where
somebody just totally went off on on an
Uber driver or on an Uber uh on an Uber
program calling them bloody taxi driver
but you know we don't want to be abusive
with our words that's never going to get
you a bounty I've never seen someone
coming in there saying listen here you
guys like you better
baby pay me some money you know and then
get paid so
um definitely you know keeping that
communication
clean and professional and and for me I
also struggle with keeping it concise
you know like I often will just be like
you know type any type and and you know
pop out this whole list but then I'll
just delete it and I'll go back and I'll
like look I could I could accomplish
this in like three sentences so I just
need to keep it clean keep it smooth and
um and I think that does a lot for the
relationship with the program too
because they've got a lot of reports
they're responding to and uh yeah that's
you know that's a big burden on them if
they have to read you know a novel every
time you send in a report so yeah I
think that's I I think we talked a
little bit in in an earlier episode
about report writing but that's one of
those things where you don't want to be
too verbose early on when your YouTube
background I think it's very easy to
feel like you need to fully explain like
every little part like how you got there
and what your thought process was and
stuff and it it makes for a cool blog
post or it makes for like a fun reading
for reading the report like in
retrospect but I think
it's better to just be clear and concise
into the point and describe the
vulnerability less than the thought
process so that they can just be like
okay this is what's going on
and understand it really easily instead
of having to read through like blocks
and blocks of text yeah yeah for sure so
so Joel let's let's put put this in
hypothetically here I'm gonna send you I
can send you right now on on on Discord
you can come look at the uh the
instacart
um Team Bounty brief
um cool look at that and tell me how you
read this what are the things you you
look at right away what things stands
out to you
um where do your eyes jump when you look
at this brief
yeah sure so I mean the first thing I'm
looking at is uh the Bounty table and
like you said is it mins or Maxes and
generally speaking what it what is their
feeling for heisen crits that I think
that's the most important thing how much
money are they putting where their mouth
is in terms of high and critical
vulnerabilities are they willing to pay
fifty thousand dollars are they willing
to pay five thousand dollars are they
willing to pay 500 they're willing to
pay fifty dollars right like
we've seen all across the board like I
think one of our buddies just the other
day was just saying oh I just got added
to this program and they pay 50 highs oh
my gosh dude it was like crazy yeah you
know yeah I understand every every
company is not just rolling in money and
stuff but that feels like a little bit
of a low priority on your security if
you ask me especially when you're trying
to incentivize people to spend time
finding security vulnerabilities on your
on your company yeah and and valid you
know validated
um POC or GTFO vulnerabilities because
you know if you're just gonna pay and I
think we've had some programs in the
past do that if you read through the
activity if you're gonna pay everybody
who submits a report like hey you missed
these headers uh hey you know SPF record
bloody blah dimar whatever
um then you're you know one you're
incentivizing bad behavior in the bug
body Community because those reports
don't get
um accepted elsewhere so people are
going to submit one report get a 50
Bounty from you and then get screwed for
the rest of their bug Bounty career
but also so you know you're going to get
a bunch of you know crappy no POC bucks
and at the end of the day that's not
what bug bounty's about bug Bounty is
about handing them I this is my opinion
maybe but I feel like this is pretty
well backed up in the community but I
feel like bug Bounty is about you know
most of the time handing them an
actionable item that that's going to
make changes in their code right away
that it oftentimes is uh attached a you
know beautiful POC that's going to
demonstrate impact
um and and you know prove something that
needs to needs to change so
um you know if you if you have these if
you have 50 bounties or whatever and
you're just throwing them out like candy
to everyone you might be paying the same
amount but I think you're getting a lot
less bang for your buck because you're
not attracting the right kind of hackers
and you're incentivizing poor behavior
in the bug Bounty Community right and I
feel like if you're paying 50 because
you you realize you have a lot of Bones
and you don't want to be going broke
then maybe address why you have so many
bones like this is one the cruxes of
like a a well-paying program right yeah
on one hand it's awesome that they are
well paying and that they have high
bounties on the other hand it's kind of
terrifying that they're paying so much
money for vulnerabilities
over and over again because you should
be stopping vulnerabilities absolutely
yeah so
um anyways I'll leave that at that we
can keep going through so yeah the next
thing I'll probably look at is
efficiency I'm basically I read it from
top down as you look at it on hacker one
or whatever so I'm looking at the
response efficiency section
and average time to First
Response that's a pretty good metric to
see sort of how like how responsive are
they how active are they if they have H1
triage then that metric kind of just
doesn't matter because triage will
always respond within SLA yeah and you
can see up at the top right hand corner
just for those of you new to hacker one
um if you if you say you know if you're
right next to this submit report button
if you look to the right of that it'll
tell you when the program launched and
it'll also say managed by hacker one if
it's managed by hacker one and and if it
is like Jill said you're always going to
get an SLA response from the triagers
and they're going to be responding
within a certain period of time so yeah
yeah and I'm glad that you brought that
up the the launch date that's another
thing I might even look at that before
the Bounty table and stuff but typically
I'm going to look at that sort of in
conjunction with the things I'm talking
about right here with efficiency and
right on to statistics so as I'm looking
at efficiency those things matter sort
of but again if it's a managed program
generally those things are going to be
kind of with than normal normal spec
it's probably going to be at least 90
percent uh hitting SLA over the last 90
days the response times are probably
going to be pretty good I you know the
longer that you do this I think the less
emphasis that I put on like I want a
program to have this paid out in a week
or whatever like I understand that
things take time I'll submit other bugs
hopefully those get paid off first
whatever yeah for sure and I think as a
professional bug Bounty as a full-time
bug Bounty Hunter you know there there's
this concept of a pipeline too that I've
heard a couple other
um bug bounty hunters full-time by
bounty hunters talk about Alex Chapman
Yasin
um them
um you know once you once you kind of
get rolling you've got unpaid bugs that
are you know sitting in the queue
waiting for them to get paid as you're
finding new bugs as you're keeping on
moving and those bugs are paying bugs of
the past are paying your current
expenses and while you're finding the
bugs for next week and the week after
that so
um a lot of people would say when
thinking about full-time book Bounty
like you know I'm sure it's important
for you to have like a quick payout it's
not really super important it is
important to me from a motivation
perspective because you know if I submit
a report I would like to get positive
feedback for that report make sure that
I'm understanding the threat model
correctly before I invest more time
um you know researching on that company
and developing my understanding of the
threat model even more
um I want to know whether I'm on the
right path so that it is important for
that metric but it's not quite important
as important for a full-time Bounty
Hunter as as pertains to like just
getting your normal salary and you know
paying your day-to-day bills yeah but I
think that is an important Point
especially if you are somebody who has
tax full time and you're going to be
hacking on one program that's something
to definitely consider if they're going
to be paying out fast or slow because
how long of a buffer do you need to have
reports in their queue for them to be
paying out before you start making money
if it takes them six months to pay out a
report well then you got to be
submitting reports for six months
because you got a delay on that by six
months yeah I'm I'm looking at the the
instacart
um thing here and I believe that this
program has a little bit of a of a delay
like the the response statistics here it
says average time to Bounty is about a
month I've actually had a a lot better
experience with them than a month it's
normally to two weeks ish for me which I
think is pretty good ideally it would be
around a week but two weeks makes a lot
of sense to me
um I know they do weekly meetings to pay
out their volumes and access severity
and that sort of thing
um so that's that's good depending on
when you submit it you might hit you
know one or one of those or two of those
if you submit right before they do their
meeting then you know might get in that
meeting being or might not so I've
definitely I definitely look at that
metric too that's one of the first
things that I I look at when I get to a
brief yeah it's it's good to hear like
that perspective as well I think it's
kind of maybe something that I take for
granted having worked on the other side
companies that have Bounty programs
where you know much more how the process
is going yeah they're they're a company
they have employees the two other things
so generally there's probably a weekly
or bi-weekly meeting where they get
together and they talk about the
bounties and stuff that's often why
there are delays on bounties because
it's a there's it's just a company you
know it's being run by employees who
have other things to do it's just a
meeting that they go to and they take
care of stuff and
um as much as that's your top Focus if
you're doing a lot of bug Bounty it's
not always their top Focus so you just
have to remember that as you're doing
your hacking and you're like where's my
bounty yeah for sure so I mean you've
worked with a couple companies that have
bug money programs is that the normal
flow every week you have a meeting or
yeah I mean sometimes depending on the
size of the program and how frequently
you get reports you might handle it just
sort of ad hoc and right off the bat
um
I think a lot of companies now are
pushing to try and pay on triage so once
they've basically validated that it's a
valid finding they try and pay the
Bounty as soon as they can and they real
they you know recognize okay this is
something valid we'll give you your
money because we understand the severity
we understand the impact and then we can
work on fixing it you can be happy and
keep hacking on us and get your money
and hopefully sort of build that Rapport
between the researcher and the program
yeah I I think Shopify was one of the
the programs that first brought that
into into place yeah it says if you
submit a valid and Bounty eligible
report we will pay you within seven days
of triage
um so that's pretty cool I would love to
see more programs uh you know uh do that
because yeah it's definitely motivating
and it's also the bigger thing for me is
validating my understanding of of the
threat model for the company and seeing
how they responded how they rate the
severity of the bugs so that I can know
what areas I need to focus on within the
app yeah 100
um cool so generally one of the last
things that I look at going back to the
the program like how I look at programs
is those program statistics about
bounties so I will usually use that in
conjunction with the launch date to
understand how old is this program and
what are their total bounties sure and
then use that to start doing some of the
averages along with the data that's in
there so for example total bounties paid
on instacart right now uh is about 400k
the program has been around for just
about a year
um it's launched in February 2022. it's
at it's March 2023 so it's about 400k a
year that's honestly
a lot of reports for that amount of time
um
and it says that their average Bounty
range is 150 to 250 yeah I think I think
that is because of the of the changes to
the Bounty table
yeah and so I don't know what it looked
like before although you you could
probably step back and look at it but I
try not to take too much of that
consideration because that average is
across all of their bounties right so of
their 400k
you can be almost certain that 80 of
those are literally just like bottom of
the barrel type low hanging fruit like
lows and that's why that average Bounty
is 150 to 250 because it's not critical
things but it they are valid reports if
you look at their top Bounty range
that's probably what when I would start
to be like okay
How likely is it that they're going to
pay something really bad and if so what
are they paying for it right so that'll
typically show like the very top end of
the bounties that they paid if they'd
ever paid a full Max crit which they
have right their body their top Bounty
range is two thousand to twenty thousand
so that means they've at least paid a
really bad medium and they've definitely
paid a 10 out of 10 critical so that
means it's out there and it exists and
they care about it and they put the
money where their mouth is and that says
a lot yeah I think also the other thing
that the average Bounty range kind of
says to me as well is if it is on this
lower end
uh you know in their low range rather
than in their medium range I think this
also speaks to the fact that they are
probably a pretty accepting program so
you know if you have something that's
kind of like I'm not sure this is like
you know super great you know I have a
pretty high standard for for bugs
um and but you know sometimes I'll find
something that's just kind of like ah
not sure I might I might take a look at
this see you know what kind of bounties
they're paying and say okay well you
know if their average range is a little
bit closer to the low that means there's
probably been more lows accepted so the
company might be more willing to pay
something that's you know a very minimal
leak in confidentiality or like a very
minimal modification in Integrity with
an attack complexity high or something
like that whereas other programs might
sort of just say Ah that's not a
vulnerability so that's another you know
way you can think through it yeah for
sure and I will generally combine that
with the next two things which is
Bounties in the last 90 days and reports
received in the last 90 days yeah to
sort of calculate a second average
that's basically a 90-day running
average of roughly how much Bounty are
they paying now like in the last three
months are they actively paying mostly
150 bounties are they paying higher than
that so in 90 days they paid 22 450
they've resolved 114 reports and their
last report was resolved six days ago so
that tells me three things one they're
paying pretty good bounties 20K in three
months that's not nothing that's a
couple thousand a month that means that
there's at least some stuff in there
that's worth looking for for sure 100
reports resolved that's a pretty good
amount of activity so just be aware that
there's lots of eyes on it and that
means that means a lot of I mean those
reports I think also include like things
that are in not just in resolved as in
like the state resolved but you know if
you put something in duplicate if you
put something informative you put
something in N A so you know think
eighty percent of those are going to be
garbage right because it's a public
program so that that can also help skew
your statistics for what actually the
bounties look like yeah but if I see
like last 90 days total bounties paid
like 3 000 that means either their
security program their security team is
insane yeah they have a small hardened
scope or nobody's attacking yeah
so you you some context clues you can
probably do some hunting to figure out
which one of those cases it is or if it
might be something completely different
that we didn't mention but these are
generally the types of things that we're
getting
in like fields from the program as we're
just sort of looking through it and then
the last thing that I generally look at
is scope
um nowadays it's very common to have
broad scope I would say it you know
maybe five years ago it most places
would have like one website or like just
our main website because there was sort
of that fear over what hackers would do
but
I think over time the the the community
has shifted and realized that it doesn't
really matter what hackers are gonna
like what bug bounty hunters are going
to do because hackers are going to do
whatever the hell they want so you have
to have everything in scope otherwise it
doesn't matter if you oh it's out of
scope my bad the hackers aren't going to
hack us then like no that doesn't matter
hackers don't know what scope is they
don't care so I mean sorry non-ethical
hackers right right we hackers good
hackers
yeah sorry bad actor yeah Bad actors are
like a scope what's that yeah um
so I scope is kind of one of those
things that I'll look at just to see if
there's anything really explicitly out
of out of scope but generally most of
the things that a company owns
oftentimes a wild card domain or a wild
card subdomain that'll be in scope and
that's always a great sign because it
just means that it's free range just
look find a vulnerability submit a
vulnerability
um and that that's the main thing that I
look for
that's all like surface level if I want
to go any deeper than that I might start
looking through the specifics like
writings within the program policy to
see what things they might have noted
down do they have specific testing
procedures do I have to put a header in
my requests any of that kind of stuff
that's what I might scan for within the
the policy text
um
but a lot of the times most of the
preliminary data that's going to
determine whether or not I'm even going
to look at a program is within those
couple of boxes it's yeah what are their
rewards what's their response like what
are their overall bounties total and
over the last 90 days and how long has
the program been out to to sort of gauge
you know
what's the what's the payout range look
like over a period of time yeah for sure
um I I was actually so I was going to
bring up another thing relating to that
and I'm not even sure I'm going to be
able to do it right now because I think
yeah that's funny bug crowd is going
through some scheduled maintenance as
we're recording this right now great
timing yeah okay okay no the the cash I
can use the cash version here
um so oh man it doesn't have the the
data I need though so I was gonna talk
about one one program
um Pinterest on bug crowd uh and kind of
talk about uh them as a as an example so
if you look at at their
setup it says that criticals are 25k or
up to 25k but then Highs are like and I
don't want to quote it wrong since I'm
not exactly even looking at it anymore
um but I want to say they were like a
couple Grand yeah here they are right
here I've got it in a screenshot two so
p1s are 20K to 25k and then p2s this is
on bug crowd are 2500 to 3500. so like a
tenth of a hot or of a critical that's
quite a quite a range yeah so one of the
things that I wanted to talk about
relating to this was I always look at
what a program pays for mediums
um as well as what they pay for crits
because and those are my two main anchor
points like the highs okay you know I I
do put I do look at that and it is
important but for me the anchor points
are mediums and crits because at the end
of the day I'm always trying to find a
crit but you know you know how we do
here at critical thinking always trying
to find the crits
um but at the end of the day when you're
finding crits in the process of finding
crits you're going to find a lot of
mediums
um and and I think it's nice to have a
good payout for the mediums
um
uh when you know when you're when you're
continuing your journey there so um my
normal standard is I want to see the
mediums
ah man actually before this episode you
know I was I was I've been saying that I
would like to see my mediums at uh 700
at least 750 but with the way that the
industry has been moving lately it might
even start you know moving a little bit
more towards a thousand
um for the mediums that's kind of where
I want to see those you know Landing uh
minimum bunny yeah yeah I mean for
minimum would be it would be great the
average you know hitting hitting around
750 to a thousand would be good so if
you look at the instacart program you
know their mediums are are 3K I had a I
had a buddy lately who submitted a
medium and got paid out 2 500
um and that's that's amazing that's a
great you know that's a great day of
hunting right there it was one day uh
one of my mentees and he found a great
bug and got a great payout for it
um and and so you know I'll a lot of
people get distracted by the big numbers
but at the end of the day you're
probably going to find more mediums and
so if you pay attention to those uh
you'll also walk away with some some
extra money in your pocket yeah I
totally agree I think you're more likely
to hit on sort of either side of a high
where you're either going to find
something that's not quite a high or
you're going to find something that is
definitely not a high and it's more of a
crit sometimes it'll be on the fence
between a high and a crit and that's
where I would emphasize report writing
and demonstrating impact and changing
vulnerabilities to try and really push
it away from the barrier and really into
the critical range
but if you know most of the time you're
going to find something that's you know
it's a vulnerability it's nothing crazy
it's whatever and it's medium or you're
gonna find something that's really
really bad and is it critical yeah yeah
for sure I totally agree
um so let's see I want to go back to
this list here because we have a little
list in the dock of of some things here
one of the things that you wrote down
that I thought was interesting was like
what is the gap between the number one
hacker and the number two number three
number four number five hacker what does
that tell you about the program yeah so
this is something that I always find
really interesting especially for public
programs
uh like 75 of the time it's always like
one of those like top three people who
has an insane Recon scanning automation
yeah system built up like nagley or try
to hack or um or today is new however
especially when it's not one of those
people that's when I get really
interested because it's somebody who's
probably spent a lot of time on that
program they're very familiar they've
done the Deep dive and they're very very
familiar with the inner workings of that
program and their infrastructure and
that's what's letting them create that
Gap right but something is happening
between like top number one and number
two oftentimes it's like a thousand reps
sometimes even more depending on the
program
and depending on the hacker and I think
those are really interesting cases to
figure out what does that person
know about the program or what does that
person figured out that lets them get a
thousand rep ahead and have so many more
crits or highs than the other people who
are hacking and looking at the same
scope and how can I replicate that kind
of you know either it's attack
methodology or how they're writing the
report or whatever so does that does
that come across as see so say you see
someone you know 2K rep the next
person's like 400 rep or something like
that does that how does that make you
feel does that deter you does that
encourage you does that have a neutral
impact on your decision to work on that
program or what it's a little bit of
both so especially if it's somebody I
know personally I'm like oh they've
already sweeped this program
yeah yeah like if it's like you know I
don't want to make Nick because I don't
wanna set that kind of precedent but you
know if it's somebody that like I'm
familiar with who I like have a lot of
respect for and their hunting skills I
would generally probably start to assume
that I'm
I'm gonna find like a rare vulnerability
if they're like that far ahead but it's
also kind of a challenge right it's like
can I find something that they haven't
found or I might reach out to them and
ask like what are some of the insights
you have about this program see if
they're willing to discuss it maybe work
together on something yeah I really like
that when I know you know just from the
life hacking scene or just from the
hacker scene in general the person that
you know really crushes the program that
I'm working on because it's always nice
to get their insight and I would I would
say like you know for example the PayPal
program
um they they have some really uh very
active uh top hackers right these guys
are I'm just checking right now to make
sure that I can
say I'm not going to say that yeah so
the guy in in first place
um you know Alex Pearson he's phenomenal
worked with him a bunch
um yeah okay so Joe Joe hash is how I'll
refer to him uh the guy in second place
with 2 300 rep you know both of those
guys are legendary at PayPal and if you
have a question about PayPal they know
it you know
um but also
there's a lot of bugs there I mean
clearly they've been finding bugs
consistently for years and and um
there's enough space for them there's
enough space for for Ron there's enough
space for all of the other people on
that list as well which means there are
bugs to be found there still
um so when I see that
I'm a little bit like sometimes I'm a
little like if someone if somebody has a
very similar testing file to me for
example space raccoon and I would
Collide on bugs all the time for a while
if space raccoon was like the number one
I'd be like eh but besides that it's
normally like like you said a challenge
yeah I also like to look at hacktivity
when I see like a top hacker and just
see are they still really active on this
program are they submitting a lot of
reports
um if so you know are they getting lots
of sometimes they have the bounties
disclosed sometimes they don't but are
they getting high high Bounty payouts
that's another good good sort of like
testing the water type thing that you
can do where just look in the activity
and see if they have bounties
um disclosed on on the reports that
they're closing and see roughly you know
what are they paying regularly are they
paying out you know some guys getting
three thousand three thousand three
thousand times he found some crazy you
know systemic vulnerability that you
should be testing for like what is it
um but that's also a really good sort of
rough test that you can do to see what's
going on at the program yeah I agree and
I and I think you nailed it that that's
a positive thing if you're seeing you
know these these these bugs you know
coming through because it means that the
program will pay if you find the Bucks
you know
um and that's really the concern here it
when you come I think it's a common
mistake that beginners make to come to
these programs to be like ah you know
I'm going to use Eric as an example
because he wouldn't mind you know
today's new has like you know 15 000 rep
here you know this is crazy I'm never
gonna find anything guys
Eric does predominantly external testing
if you log in if you pass the login
screen you've probably seen more of that
app than Eric has and so like and that's
his thing and he crushes it and he finds
amazing bugs on so many different
targets but he doesn't look internally
so you know if you see today's new that
I I remember actually pretty clearly a
time on a tweet where some you know some
new person newer to Buck Bounty says
tweeted out something like when you get
a new private program invite and then
you see this and it's like a picture of
Eric at number one with like you know
however many rep I was like no bro
you're just don't pass on that invite
like just that just means I have lots of
dangling domains don't worry about it
exactly just log into the app you know
like so I think that's I think that's a
common misconception that hopefully
we've cleared up here
um yeah and I I like one of the things
about the activity that I really like on
bug crowd specifically is that in their
disclosed things separate from the the
Bounty they also talk a little bit about
what part of the scope the report's on
so you can get a rough idea for where
are people looking where are the bugs
surfacing themselves is for the API is
it in the front end is it on the mobile
app is like wherever a Crowder was that
synack I think it's but I think they
actually both do oh do they know cynic
does it as well snack even I think they
disclose part of the report title or
something like that really okay yeah but
but bug crowd will basically just say
like in this scope they got this bounty
they're actually I think they just say
like what what severity it was I don't
even know if they say the Bounty but
regardless it's just a little more
information that will help you gleam
sort of where you might want to focus or
not focus depending on what you're
seeing yeah for sure and and I actually
or is yeah here it is I had something in
the dock as well so the known issues tab
is really cool on bug crowd as well I
really wish hacker one would Implement
something like this where there's a
little bit transparency on how many
unique issues there are outstanding that
have not been resolved yet in the in the
program because
one of the things that I really want to
know when I come into a program is like
hey are you fixing bugs you know what
are the chances of me coming in here and
finding a dupe like I did this
um this past week and lost out on a big
big payout uh crit because they're not
fixing the bugs
um that's really painful for me and even
as an experienced Bug Hunter you know
I've gotten probably at this point
hundreds and hundreds of dupes and uh
you know uh I guess maybe I've the pain
of it has been a little bit uh you know
removed from me for a little while
because I haven't had one that really
punched me in the gut lately but this
one really took the wind out of me and
stopped my testing for a couple days
because I was just really like man you
know why why is this happening
um and so you know it definitely happens
and you just kind of that's part of the
game you got to get up you got to keep
working on it but I think something like
this with the known issues um indicator
for hacker one would really add a lot of
transparency to that issue and also
Force programs to stay on top of
resolving or else maybe their SLA light
would go red or something like that yeah
I think overall one of the one of the
more positive Trends I've seen from
programs is that they have
slowly added certain things that are
common across either a program policy or
submission process into the like
application itself and what I mean by
that is for example
integrity
when you submit a bug they have
additional fields for like what was your
IP address during testing and like you
can you know add customizations and
stuff like that into the the actual like
Forum that the hacker is typing into
when they submit a bug and those types
of things probably on hacker one would
just be in your report template or
something when they go to create a new
report and just that additional little
step where it's integrated into the
application where it's an extra field or
it's an extra tab or something that you
can click like known issues right
instead of putting that in your policy
it's a tab on on the program page that
says these are the known issues so as a
hacker I don't have to read through each
program's policy and decide have they
put known issues in their policy page or
have they skipped over that entirely are
there things I need to know about
instead I can just click the known
issues Tab and see what they've listed
there absolutely agree having some
standardization for that would be huge
and it would also allow you in a lot of
cases to programmatically filter you
know where
if you're doing the hacking you're
you're pretty you're pretty familiar
with apis and how they work and such and
so you know there's when you're building
out your own automation or you're you
know really searching for a program to
to go after
um having something like that could help
you filter down and in your own
automation as well
yeah for sure
um so anything that programs get or
platforms can do to sort of standardize
that type of stuff make it easier to
find the information I know hacker want
to added a scope tab recently which is a
nice little shift so you don't have to
scroll to the bottom and stuff like that
yeah I think that's cool the scope tab
how do I feel about the scope tab man I
don't know I feel like the scope tab is
a little
um
a little iffy it's a little weird
because like
it's helpful and it's nice but then
there's also scope in the policy still
and so it kind of feels like all right I
still got to read the whole policy and I
can't just jump right to the scope so I
think I think hacker one needs to make
the full switch over if they're going to
do it because that you know now I just
have two things to read and one of them
isn't in my immediate field of view you
know when I get to the page 100 yeah um
let me see here so the other thing one
of the other things that I kind of
wanted to talk about was uh Hunter nice
to haves on a program this is this a if
a program has this there's a really good
chance that they're a good program to
work with so what do I mean by that so
um here are some examples
I've seen programs drop treasure maps
before which will say like hey these and
even if it's not a treasure map if they
just say hey these are core assets these
are the assets that we really care about
um
that's really nice to have because it
allows you to know okay you know if I
pop a crit on you know www dot
instacart.com obviously the www is
important but like if I pop a crit on
you know okay hold on let's let's look
because instacart actually has this this
type of section in there which I really
appreciate
um I'm just gonna control that for core
assets yeah here it is right here so
admin.instaccart.com would be a big a
big Target
um
they include their Shoppers mobile app
very explicitly
um and so you know when they have stuff
like that it's really helpful for you to
be able to uh focus on the correct
targets and you don't have to work as
much I talked to you earlier about the
threat model right like you don't have
to work as much to figure out the threat
model you know okay if it's in this
domain it's probably like you know the
Golden Goose of sorts you know like this
is the thing they want us to go after
and get yeah that was kind of exactly
what I was going to say I think there's
definitely two perspectives there's a
company side which is like should we
really be emphasizing the things that
are really critical for our company
publicly and then there's the attacker
side which is this makes it so or the
researcher side which makes it so much I
keep saying attacker but yeah I mean the
terms it's both ambiguous yeah yeah but
it's it's also like how do I make my
report more impactful easier so they're
basically drawing the lines and saying
here's what you need to do to make it
the most impactful report it's you know
customer data or it's this specific
website or whatever it's being able to
do this certain thing right and those
are great guidelines and guiding factors
for
steering your testing in a way that
makes it impactful and meaningful the
whole time so if you're testing all of
your bugs in a way that's going to give
it the most impact You're Gonna Save
Yourself the time of having to escalate
those bugs later
um and you're going to get obviously
higher bounties the more that you do
that yeah for sure the the other thing
that I kind of wanted to point out was
um there's some programs that will
give you free features for their for
their premium and I think that's great
because you know one of the things that
we talk about here in the podcast a lot
is like
pay the pay the freaking subscription
fee right if you're if you're going to
be hacking an app and there's like some
section you know where it's like oh pay
50 bucks and get access to like super
premium stuff
pay that [__] like like every single
time I've done that it has resulted in a
bad vault yep um without exception
really
um I've made you know 150 times you know
150x return on investment from that 50
bucks you know that you put in there
because a lot of times they're that
extra little piece of friction is what
the step that other researchers aren't
willing to take and um is really
separating you from the the critical
vulnerabilities there but
another step that the researchers often
don't take which is also you know a
differentiating factor is doing what is
required to get access to these test
features through the companies a lot of
times which is send the company an email
and say hey could I please have a
premium account and if you do that and
they say yes and they give you the
premium account well you just saved
yourself 150 bucks or whatever it costs
and you also got access to the premium
feature so I wanted to shout out
another one of my my favorite programs
semrush this is a um this is a program
that does search engine optimization uh
it's a search engine optimization
application their bounties are pretty
good I normally like to see highs or
crits uh crits in the five figure range
and highs a little bit higher than they
do but their mediums are are spot on and
they're they're pretty willing to give
out mediums
um so they will they will if you you
know reach out to them give you a
premium account to test the app with
um so definitely keep that in mind uh it
when you're when you're looking at that
program I'm not even sure they say it in
their
policy anymore
yeah that's pretty that's actually a
really cool approach I don't think I've
ever I've ever done that where I've like
approach them directly because most of
the time I assume that they'll never
give me it but that's uh that's
something I'm gonna have to try because
uh I kind of like that approach
um I think kind of tangentially attached
to that is if you see programs that auto
seed test accounts
um yeah like Shopify for example is
great great example where if you sign up
with an at we are hacker1.com email
they pre-seed your account with like
test data they I think they mark it in
the back end somehow to make it have
like phenomenal yeah I mean however they
do it it shows that they care right it
shows that they have gone the extra mile
they've worked with their engineering
team they've made explicit efforts to
integrate bug Bounty into the
engineering workflow to make it so that
you can do testing easier without as
many hurdles and find better bugs and
that shows a lot right it shows that
even like even though they might have to
pay more money that's fine they'd rather
have the security and pay more money
than not have the security or make it
harder so that's just like a really
awesome thing to see yeah absolutely and
I did find the the um
the section in the semrush
policy it's down at the bottom promo
code they'll give you a promo code with
a valid submission which I think is a
good I think that's a really good sort
of indicator as well you know I feel
like they they
you know if you're just giving out free
accounts to everybody then it might
invalidate your business model a little
bit that almost becomes the volume
itself there but if you do it with a
valid report submission it proves that
the researcher is actually putting time
into the program and has earned you know
an account and uh so yeah very
Innovative there really liked to see
that with semrush cool um what are some
of the things going off the off our list
again what are some of the things that
um like you look for if you're hacking
uh if you're going back to a Target are
you looking for like new scope
um if they're in the news like what are
the types of stuff you look for yeah I
think you know I often have with the
live hacking event circuit I have to
leave instacart and go and and spend
time on different programs and then come
back to it and sometimes other programs
kind of steal my attention away for a
little bit but oftentimes I revert back
to instacart
um and in the meantime I you know I'll
be looking one of the things that's
really cool is GAO has a feature where
you can kind of look at recent URLs that
were indexed so I'll use that sometimes
to kind of you know sniff out new
features I'll look like you like you
very shortly mentioned in the news for
new features like ah you know insta card
just launched XYZ and then kind of go
after that
um but I'll also go back to the places
where I was familiar with where I you
know dug in deep the last time I hacked
there and you know I feel like your mind
will kind of look at that and be like
hey that's a little bit different than
it was before and you know then you
start to see like okay this is sort of
new feature added on here and I've had
that happen a couple times where you
know just your your eye from having
tested that extensively
um is is trained to know where that new
stuff is is and and kind of get
attracted to that new functionality so
that's kind of that's kind of where I
look it's really awesome to hear like
that that perspective that there are
like those kind of stable programs that
you can just keep going back to and and
enjoy hacking and find new bugs because
I think it's it's a common misconception
that if you do too like too much hacking
so to speak on one program that is going
to dry up and it can happen but it
depends on the program it's about
finding a good program right it's just
kind of what we're talking about and
finding one that you can hack long term
on and keep finding good bugs keep
providing value to the company keep
having an enjoyable time making money
provide a living all that kind of stuff
yeah for sure I I almost want to
disagree with you there that that it's
about the program I think in some cases
it is about the program like if their
development cycle is like they push new
features like once every quarter or like
you know once every half year or
something like that then it can be
absolutely about the program but a lot
of the time man I think it's about
people getting complacent and saying
like you know you go in there and you
like pwn some stuff and you find a crate
in a couple highs and mediums and blah
blah and then you like sit there and
you're like all right that program's
done you know but that's a mistake you
know you're just getting you're just
starting to understand the mistakes that
the vulnerabilities you know that are
there the mistakes that this company is
making and if you dive in again and you
go deeper and deeper and deeper and
start trying these same techniques you
know maybe an idor worked in a specific
type of endpoint well great you know
let's let's try to find other endpoints
that sort of resemble this
um you know do they have patch reversal
issues do they have caching issues these
are all things that can be you know
systemic across the the programs in can
be a continuous source of bugs
especially eye doors and access control
issues
um you know those are those are big if a
company doesn't have that figured out
you know with middleware or with
something like that then there's
definitely a big potential for
reoccurring bugs there
yeah yeah that's a great observation
it's nice to hear that like you know
sometimes it is a program but it's also
you you know like just don't don't let
yourself slack right yeah all right we
are at an hour two let's see
um let's see if there's anything else
that wanted to hit oh the other cool
thing that I wanted to just go ahead and
give a shout out for two two things here
ssrf sheriff and somebody I know has a
pretty cool GitHub repo about that right
I don't yeah I couldn't imagine who that
is oh hey it's this guy named technology
that's crazy genius love that guy so um
a little self promo here while I was at
Uber for one of our live hacking events
we wrote this thing called an ssrf
Sheriff it was an idea originally
um proposed by Franz and essentially
what it was is an internal service
that's designed to make testing ssrf
easier so it's something that you would
spin up within your infrastructure from
a company side and you would provide the
researchers with an internal IP address
host name all of the above hopefully
both
and it responds to basically any type of
request so it'll respond to images with
very various different images usually
with a secret identifier that is within
the image
um it responds with that identifier in
headers in the body it has different
mime types and the whole reason for this
is that basically it's designed to adapt
to any ssrf situation if you have uh
basically anything but a blind ssrf and
you can see the response in any way
whether that's an image whether that's
the headers whether that's whatever
the goal is that can I hit this service
and if so I should be able to get this
secret string back that will prove
definitively that I have an ssrf right
if you can provide that secret string to
the the program you can say here's your
secret string bam that's it no questions
asked the POC or GTFO mentality once
again here is like if you can hit that
and and you get this back then boom you
know and that that really that instant
feedback for us as hackers as well is
really valuable because you know we
could spend hours sitting there poking
at with an uh you know blindnesses are
trying to prove internal impact or you
could set up the server we could hit it
in in two minutes and have that sort of
decided so I love to see when programs
set up that that tool that that Joel
made it's pretty easy to set up really
simple you just you know if you've got
sort of devops in your organization you
can you can spin it up real easily
um and definitely something that adds a
lot of value okay the other thing that I
wanted to shoot out uh before we before
we move along is documentation and you
know I love documents you I love being a
good document man
um and so or a bad one yeah I mean you
know bad documentation too it's better
than no documentation and most of most
websites do have documentation
um
what's better is when they give you sort
of Internal Documentation documentation
for their API that maybe stuff that
contains like graphql schemas or you
know maybe like a postman file or like
you know Swagger or something like that
um that those are all very helpful
because we can see as we start you know
ascending or um as we start ascending
um as we start assessing the application
um you know you you
start finding
um I can keep myself Rising off my chair
already stuck on the Joel cut it out man
yeah as you start assessing the
application you get various you know you
see various common threads across across
the app and it's easier to see all of
those you know when you've got the API
documentation you can see okay well
maybe
um you know API calls that are
structured a little bit like this would
be more vulnerable than others so very
very helpful there and it also helps us
be thorough as well you know sometimes
you just sit down and you grind and you
just make you know a replay tab or a
repeater tab for every single API
endpoint that you have and you you know
fuzz the crap out of those and that's
the kind of testing you want from the
program side that's what you know really
gets you some very thorough results
um and and so you can really enable that
with a Swagger file or graphql schema
yeah and this was reminding me of
something this is probably more specific
to live hacking events I feel like this
fell off a little bit but when I was at
Uber one of the things that I pushed for
was providing Zone files to researchers
yeah and
um this is a little bit trickier to do
for a public program to keep it like
maintained and up to date there actually
was I don't remember
that Uber does this now I don't know
typically but but they basically we
created a tool
that would automatically pull like a
list of all the domains and then keep it
in a file up to date so that there's no
question about like am I missing
something because my recon's bad or my
word list is bad we'll give you a full
list of every single domain that exists
go ahead and find bugs on it and that
removes just you know another barrier it
makes it the security
yeah and it shows that you know security
is valued it doesn't matter if it's like
a complicated domain we care about the
vulnerability within that domain let's
let's see what you got
um and sort of just you know again
putting money where your mouth is
absolutely yeah I totally dig that too
that really puts everyone on an equal
playing field as far as Recon goes
because you know a lot of people have
access to specific I won't call it out
specifically but there's you know
certain API services that are out there
that are very very very very very very
expensive
um that will give you access to a lot
more domains than other people have
access to
um and and so you know doing something
like releasing those own files puts
everyone in equal playing ground and
then it's the it's the person that can
hack the app the best that that finds
the bug right and that's kind of like
what Jason was talking about last week
one of my favorite quotes from last week
was you know the whole point of Recon is
to find more apps to hack you know and
and um uh I think
giving giving the Zone files really
proves that yeah don't make it a Recon
game make it a security game you know
yeah absolutely
um okay cool I think we'll cut the rest
of that dock there and uh let me talk
about this report really quick and then
we'll we'll peace out so
um I just wanted to I want to talk about
this report on the Pod because I I
thought this was really creative and
this actually wasn't something that I'd
seen before or at least I hadn't seen it
in a while
um this is report one eight six one nine
seven four we'll link it in the in the
description of the podcast but it's a
report uh
to pixiv which is a a Japanese program
I've actually looked at them a lot
because their their site is in Japanese
um and uh this is a in this report
essentially and I missed this bug just
to be clear which makes me a little
salty
um but there's an oauth flow
and what happens is when the user
completes the oauth flow there's
actually or in the return URL there's a
path driver so that you can do that
allows you to hit any endpoint on the uh
you know Target domain right it's only
validating you know hey does it start
with bloody blah right so in this in the
in the example here they have slash
Pixar callback and then that's you know
where the cutoff ends there and then
he's able to dot slash dot slash dot
slash and then provide a different item
number now this used to be a lot more
impactful
um when uh the browsers were sharing the
the refer cross origin
um and you could just you know leak the
uh oauth token via a open redirect or
something like that then the browser
stopped adding the path and the query
parameter to the referrer because of
security issues and that fixed a lot of
these issues but the uh the report
writer here has a really Innovative
solution he there's some uh application
there's some feature in the application
where you can set up a Google analytics
tracking ID on that page in this cool
this is cool right
um and when you put up your Google
analytics tracking ID on there so you
can get analytics on how many people are
visiting your items or whatever
um
what that does is it takes the URL and
it leaks it to the attacker so I think
this is going to be and you know Franz
already talks about this in his post
message
um uh you know expose like very long
thing that he released on on how to leak
you know you are oauth URLs via post
message
um but I think there's also going to be
an another area where this becomes you
know where these sort of Bones
essentially URI leak or something like
that
um becomes a thing because they're often
able to chain with oauth and you often
find yourself able to insert or get
vulnerable information into the URL and
then you know have that leaked if you
can find a way to get it out so it's
just another attack Vector for you guys
to be thinking about as your as you're
bug hunting and and um you know anytime
you can leak the UR the URL definitely
think about oauth tokens or think about
sensitive information getting placed
there yeah that's a super creative
um like attack scenario I don't think I
probably would have thought that was
even possible
um but it's like one of those unique
application features that you know the
more familiar you are with the
application the fact that he knew or
they knew that you could put a Google
analytics tracking ID with your custom
Google analytics and yeah track those
URL that's an awesome like creative way
and to exploit this and it was marked as
a high because you know yeah it's a
great finding and I've worked with the
pixit program a little bit like no I
mean I'm not gonna diss him but I've had
some problems with with them so the fact
that they acknowledge this has a high is
really you know one a step in the right
direction two shows that how well
written the report is and the mentality
of the attacker
um which is which is really cool so um
kudos to this guy it definitely this is
another Ransom and I try to keep it
concise because we're getting you know a
little far here but you know you know
how we do here we just go
um one of the things that I wanted to
talk about is how like in this scenario
the attacker realizes the hacker
realizes that uh
you know when stuff when sensitive
information makes its way into the URL
there's risk there when when you know
and when user input gets reflected into
the the Dom or to the body there's risk
there and I think um a lot of the ways
that people address learning how to hack
is like okay xss you know okay idor and
they they think about these
vulnerability categories when in in a
lot of times the way that you're coming
up with these big brain like crazy
creative bugs is you're not thinking
about it so much as from the perspective
of like ah this is a long time that I'm
familiar with you're coming at it from
this perspective like okay when
a application takes attacker information
and puts it in a request that they make
on the server side
sketchy stuff happens when that data
gets reflected into the Doms sketchy
stuff happens when sensitive information
gets put into the URL sketchy stuff
happens and that's you know so as you're
as you're starting to learn how to hack
those indicators should start triggering
like okay this is weird Okay this is
sketchy oh there's post messages flying
here that's interpage communication you
know there's an attack Vector there and
I think focusing on those instead of
focusing on vulnerability types can more
can help you become more of a of a I I I
don't want to use the word generic but
like a sort of a jack of all traits
hacker you know someone who can really
under come that isn't like a textbook
hacker that just reads the textbook and
finds the idors by replacing the number
right
um so if you're really shooting for the
stars
um understanding those threat models in
the browser in the app you know in all
pieces of the application is really
important I think yeah it's like that
more adaptive kind of style of hacking
it's not just that you're not a just a
scanner right you're not just necessary
or whatever you're you're a hacker and
you're you're supposed to be coming up
with more creative because those
automated systems don't worry they're
out there there's a million of them and
they're doing it all at the same time
like that that attack service is almost
certainly covered yeah what you should
be focusing on is the more creative
things that those scanners are not going
to find that are going to provide real
deep inherent value to the security team
into the to the company who's dealing
with this vulnerability right it shows
you know I think this report is a great
example of it where it's just showing
that you've gone one step further right
like anybody could have just tested
oauth flow okay it doesn't have a
redirect and if it can it's just on a
path okay whatever next done skip right
but this researcher specifically was
like hang on a second that is weird
that's there is risk right how can I
exploit that risk
yeah phenomenal really really well done
there
um good good tips to end the podcast
with uh you got anything else you want
to say before we balance Joel no I think
that's it all right sweet that's the pod